Guide to the George Washington University Publications collection, 1924-2017 RG0154
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- International Topics, Series 2
  - Standardization drivers, levers, and performance: a conceptual framework and some preliminary findings by A.N.M. Waheeduzzaman and Pradeep A. Rau., 1998-01-01; Series 2; 32 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    "January 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (page 32).
  - Marketing research ethics by Pradeep A. Rau, Daniel R. Kane., 1998-01-01; Series 2; 28 unnumbered pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    "January 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 26-28).
  - Home sweet home: firm domesticity and demand for experienced key managers by Douglas M. Sanford, Jr., 1998-03-01; Series 2; 34 pages: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    "March 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 23-29).
  - Central bank vulnerability and the credibility of commitments: a value-at-risk approach to currency crises by Mario I. Blejer and Liliana Schumacher. and the Credibility of Commitments: A Value-At-Risk Approach to Currency Crises, 1998-04-01; Series 2; 43 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    "April 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 40-43).
  - Seigniorage and conventional taxation with multiple exogenous shocks by Reid W. Click., 1998-06-01; Series 2; 37 pages, [3] pages of plates: illustrations; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    "June 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 27-30).
  - Negotiating a joint venture in China: the problem of market access by John Allee and Douglas M. Sanford, Jr., 1998-06-01; Series 2; 33 pages: illustrations, map; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    "June 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 29-30).
  - Bridging the Pacific: a comparison of advertising agency-client relationships in the U.S. and Korea by Douglas M. Sanford, Jr., Sungjin Cho, Sujin Kim, Inchang Yeo, and Lynda Maddox.: A Comparison of Advertising Agency-Client Relationships in the U.S. and Korea, 1998-07-01; Series 2; 29 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    "July 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 19-21).
  - Financial innovation in an emerging market: petroleum derivatives trading in the 19th century by Robert J. Weiner., 1998-09-01; Series 2; 25 pages: illustrations, map; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    "September 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 18-22).
  - Are principals principled? by William E. Wilson and Peter Lohrey., 1998-10-01; Series 2; [13] pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    "October 1998.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Equity announcements and information signalling by Michael Mazzeo and William E. Wilson., 1998-10-01; Series 2; 19, [6] pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    "October 1998."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Equity announcements and analyst expectations by Michael Mazzeo and William E. Wilson., 1998-11-01; Series 2; 14, [4] pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    "November 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 14).
  - Latin American corporate strategy under the new regionalism by Fernando Robles., 1998-11-01; Series 2; 38 pages; 29 cm. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    "November 1998."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 30-33).
  - Determinants of market competitiveness in an environmentally sustainable tourism industry by Salah S. Hassan., 1999-04-01; Series 2; 24 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    "April 1999."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 22-24).
  - Corporate community: a theory of the firm uniting profitability and responsibility by William E. Halal., 1999-04-01; Series 2; 20, [14] pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    "April 1999."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 19-20).
  - Framing classical hypothesis testing methods and rejecting them for managerial decision making by David Zalkind., 2002-05-01; Series 2; 19 pages: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    "May 2002."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 19).
  - A long-range development plan for the School of Government and Business Administration of the George Washington University prepared by a committee consisting of professors: Guy Black [and others]., 1972-08-01; Series 2; 112 leaves in various foliations; 30 cm (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Social Programs, Series 3
  - An experimental study of sensitivity of survey techniques in measuring drinking practices, by Arthur D. Kirsch, Carol H. Newcomb [and] Ira H. Cisin., 1965-03-01; Series 3; iii, 20 pages 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American drinking practices; a national survey of behavior and attitudes related to alcoholic beverages, by Don Cahalan, Ira H. Cisin [and] Helen M. Crossley., 1967-06-01; Series 3; xii, 355, 20, 2 pages 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes bibliographical references (pages 237-239).
  - Differences in sub-group drinking patterns in a U.S. national survey by Don Cahalan., 1968-09-01; Series 3; 16, [11] leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "Conducted ... under Grant No. 3M-9080 from the National Institute of Mental Health."; "Prepared for presentation at the 28th International Congress on Alcohol and Alcoholism, Washington, September 15-20, 1968."; Cover title.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 26-27).
  - Correlates of problems related to drinking: findings of a national survey: final draft by Don Cahalan, study director., 1969-09-15; Series 3; 18 leaves, 16 pages; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    "Paper prepared for presentation at the Annual Meeting of the North American Association of Alcoholism Programs, Vancouver, B.C., September 15, 1969."; Caption title.; Work supported by grants from the National Institute of Mental Health.; Includes bibliographical references (pages 15-16).
  - Drinking practices and accidental injuries by Berthold Brenner, Ira H. Cisin, and Carol Newcomb., 1969-08-01; Series 3; 6, [14] leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    "Transcript of a presentation at the session on Alcohol Use and Accidents of the Society for the Study of Social Problems, Miami Beach, Florida, Aug. 28, 1966."; Caption title.
  - America on the rocks: a study analysis and report on the development of a methodology for the dissemination of information to the professions and the public on the use and abuse of alcohol in the American society: a comprehensive final report, HSM-42-71-109., 1975-02-28; Series 3; approximately 200 leaves in various foliations: illustrations, maps; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Prepared by George Washington University's Dept. of Medical and Public Affairs under grant numbers HSM-42-71-109 from the National Institute of Mental Health.
  - Final Report -- Factors maintaining drinking in alcoholic families: final report by principal investigator: Peter Steinglass. in Alcoholic Families, 1978-03-31; Series 3; 82 leaves: graphs; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 7)
    "Supported by NIAAA grant #2 R01 AA 01441," from the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism.; Cover title.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 81-82).
  - Proceedings of the National Conference of Vocational Rehabilitation and State Alcoholism Agency Directors on "Coordinated Rehabilitation Services for People with Alcoholism", 1973-03-01; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Project Report: Demonstration of emergency care program for public intoxication offenders and other acute alcohol intoxication cases: project summary of final project report and final evaluation report by Alcohol Detoxification Center; Doris S. Bradley, director; evaluators: Clinton A. Neyman, Jr., Ann M. Riordan, Education Division, Social Research Group, George Washington University. Center, 1970-03-01; Series 3; 7 leaves; 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Issued with Demonstration of emergency care program for public intoxication offenders and other acute alcohol intoxication cases: final project report [and] final evaluation report. Washington, D.C., 1970.; Report submitted to Law Enforcement Assistance Administration, U.S. Dept. of Justice under LEAA Grant #019.
  - Alcohol advertising and marketing: consumer and government involvement prepared by Bonnie Wilford, Jacqueline Morgan., 1992-11-01; Series 3; 66 pages: maps; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
    "November 1992."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - The Coping catalog: a guide to resources in the greater Washington area for alcohol, drug, and other addiction problems by editor, Joseph L. Wright., 1983; Series 3; 266 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Fourth edition edited by Eleanor R. Edelstein and Joseph Wright.; Includes indexes.
  - Alcohol and alcohol abuse, substance abuse, controlled substances: a summary of selected 1981 laws by Gail E. Toff., Series 3; 8 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Supported by a grant from the Office of Research and Demonstrations, Health Care Financing Administration, Dept. of Health and Human Services (HCFA grant 18-P-98148/3-01).; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Drug abuse current alerting service: final report prepared by the Science Communication Division, George Washington University., 1974-08-01; Series 3; 104, [5] leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Prepared for the Office of Naval Research under contract numbers N00014-67-A-0214-0017.; Report for the period 1 September 1972 - 31 August 1974.
  - The determinants of teenage smoking behavior by J. Howard Beales III., 1996-06-01; Series 3; 53, [1] pages; 29 cm. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    "June 1996."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 53-54).
  - Concomitants of marijuana use among Americans aged 18-29 by Hugh J. Parry, Ira H. Cisin, Mitchell B. Balter., 1971; Series 3; 26 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
    "Special report D-1."; Cover title.; Work supported by grants from National Institute of Mental Health.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Families at risk: analysis of state initiatives to aid drug-exposed infants and their families prepared by Bonnie Baird Wilford, Jacqueline Morgan., 1993-06-01; Series 3; 116 pages: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 16)
    "June 1993."; Includes bibliographical references (pages 107-116).
  - Public experience with psychoactive substances: a nationwide study among adults and youth prepared by Herbert I. Abelson, Ronald B. Atkinson., 1975-08-01; Series 3; volumes: illustrations (Box 1, Folder 17)
    "RA 3698."; Research implemented as a subcontract with Social Research Group, the George Washington University, for the National Institute on Drug Abuse, Division of Research, Behavioral and Social Sciences Branch.; part 1. Main findings.
  - Drug use and drug programs in the Washington Metropolitan Area: an assessment: executive summary., 1988-02-01; Series 3; vii, 31 pages: illustrations; 23 cm (Box 1, Folder 18)
    "February 1988."; Executive summary of a report by Peter Reuter [and others]; published: Santa Monica, CA: Rand: [1988].; Includes bibliographical references.
  - The Gnawing Paradox of Homelessness in America, 1990-10-01; Series 3 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The structural context of city adoption of War on Poverty and National Flood Insurance programs by R. Scott Frey., 1980; Series 3; 46, [6] leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Financially supported by the George Washington University Facilitating Fund.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 30-46).
  - Financing public welfare: 1970 projections, by Selma J. Mushkin and Robert Harris., 1965-07-01; Series 3; vii, 58 pages maps 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    "The Council of State Governments in cooperation with the National Association of Counties, the National League of Cities, the United States Conference of Mayors, the George Washington University."; Includes bibliographical references.; Also issued online.
  - A legislative snapshot: nursing homes, reimbursement, rate regulation, and financial issues by David V. Haas., 1980; Series 3; 15 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Caption title.; Cover title reads: Nursing homes.; Covers laws passed in 1979.; Supported by a grant from the Health Care Financing Administration, DHEW, HCFA Grant 18-P-27 321/3.
  - A curriculum in social gerontology: for those interested in health care for the aged by Carrol M. Mickey., 1967; Series 3; vi, 155 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 23)
    "A study supported by Community Health Services, Bureau of State Services, Public Health Service, Community Health Services and Facility Act, Project Grant Number CH 09-3 C-65."; "The editing and publication of the Curriculum in Social Gerontology was made possible by the W.K. Kellogg Foundation."; Includes bibliographical references and index.
  - Facts, issues, and concepts of aging: a learning guide first draft; prepared by the National Council on the Aging, Incorporated in conjuction [sic] with the George Washington University School of Medicine and Health Sciences, Office of Allied Health Programs., 1975-06-01; Series 3; 411 pages in various pagings; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 24)
    "Funding for preparation of this manual provided under D.H.E.W., Administration on the Aging, Contract No. 90-A-347/01."; Cover title: Appendix G: Workshop trainers manual.; Includes bibliographical references.; Photocopy of typescript.
  - Multi-disciplinary and interprofessional career training program in gerontology (DHEW 90A1097): final report to Office of Education and Training, Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare submitted by the George Washington University, School of Medicine and Health Sciences., 1979-10-01; Series 3; 24, 14, [7] leaves; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Report covers period from Aug. 1, 1977 through Aug. 31, 1979.
  - Growing older in Greater Washington by George Grier., 1989-05-01; Series 3; ix, 41 pages: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 26)
    "May 1989."
  - Premature retirement: does a positive attitude ensure a successful transition? by Philip W. Wirtz and Ivan Charner., 1989; Series 3; 31 leaves: illustrations; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Includes bibliographical references (leaves 28-30).
  - Directory of services and resources to the Asian Pacific American community in the metropolitan Washington region by the COG Human Relations Committee; [authors, Ann P. Rall, Ivy L. Gilmore, and Robert L. Cosby]., 1995-06-01; Series 3; v, 91 pages; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    "June 1, 1995."
  - Rural women's groups as potential change agents: a study of Colombia, Korea and the Philippines by Marion Ruth Misch, principal investigator, and Joseph B. Margolin, co-investigator., 1975-05-31; Series 3; xv, 106 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 29)
    [Final] report submitted to Dr. Bernard Wilder, Technical Assistance Bureau, U.S. Agency for International Development.; Work performed under Project #931-17-670-591-73.; Includes bibliographical references (leaves 102-106).
- Health Services, Series 4
  - Survey of health block grant implementation by Peggy O'Kane., 1981-10-01; Series 4; 10, 9 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Supported by a grant from the Office of Research, Demonstrations and Statistics, Health Care Financing Administraion, DHHS, HFCA Grant 18-P-97321/3-03.
  - Private health insurance benefits for alcoholism, drug abuse and mental illness by Mary Lou Cooper., 1979-07-01; Series 4; 34 pages; 26 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Addendum sheet inserted.; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Prepaid group practice: an analysis as a delivery system; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans, by Leon Gintzig [and] Robert G. Shouldice., 1971-11-01; Series 4; x, 223 pages illustrations 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - State comprehensive and catastrophic health insurance programs: an overview by T. Van Ellet., 1981-10-01; Series 4; 129 pages: illustrations; 26 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
    "October 1, 1981."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Health insurance regulation: an overview of 1992 state legislative activity., 1993-01-01; Series 4; 48 pages (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Health insurance mandates: an overview of 1992 state legislative activity., 1993-01-01; Series 4; 30 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 5)
    "January 1993."
  - Certificate of need: an overview of 1992 state legislative activity written by Constance Thomas., 1993-01-01; Series 4; 33 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Chronic care: an overview of 1992 state legislative activity written by Alison Patrucco Barnes., 1993-01-01; Series 4; 60 leaves (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Preliminary form of final report, Contract HSM-110-69-247.; [pt. 1, id est] Introduction. Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; conclusions and recommendations.--[pt. 2, id est] part leaves Reports on individual prepaid group practices. 4 volume --[pt. 3, id est] part 2. Comparison of prepaid group practices.--[pt. 4, id est] part 3. Prepaid group practices: data handling activities. 2 volume.
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Prepaid group practice plans: a comparative analysis; the reports and comparisons of selected aspects of several prepaid group practice plans and a study of their data handling activities Completed by the Research Division, Department of Health Care Administration, George Washington University., 1971-11-01; Series 4; 4 parts in 8 volumes: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Medicaid: A Legislative Snapshot at Medicaid Legislation, 1979; Series 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Medicaid: A Legislative Snapshot of 1979 State Enactments, Series 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Medicaid: A Snapshot of 1980 Laws, Series 4 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - DRGs and the Medicaid program by Donald L. Zimmerman., 1984-06-01; Series 4; ii, 68 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 18)
    "June 1984."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - Medicaid: an overview of 1992 state legislative activity written by Alison Patrucco Barnes., 1993-01-01; Series 4; 46 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - State strategies for containing health care costs: a review of selected state programs by Connie J. Wessner [and others]., 1991-12-01; Series 4; 55 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 20)
    "December 1991."
  - State Medicaid policies for the reimbursement of psychiatric services provided in a general hospital: results of a 1993 survey by Claire Helf., Series 4; 139 pages (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - A policymaker's guide on HIVAIDS for the 1990s written by Lisa Bowleg and Kate Cauley; graphics by Helen Barvasa., 1992-04-01; Series 4; 64 pages: illustrations, maps; 29 cm (Box 1, Folder 22)
    "April 1992."; Previous edition: A policymaker's guide on AIDS / Mona Rowe and Caitlin Ryan. 1989.; Includes bibliographical references (page 64).
  - A summary of HIVAIDS laws from the 1992 state legislative sessions by Lisa Bowleg., 1993-01-01; Series 4; xi, 56 pages: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 23)
    "January 1993."; Includes index.
  - Emergency medical services by Jane Morgenstern., 1980; Series 4; 19 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Supported by the office of Research, Demonstrations and Statistics, Health Care Financing Administration, Dept. of Health and Human Services, HCFA Grant 18-P-97321/3-03.
  - A snapshot of 1979 state legislative enactments relating to the confidentiality of medical records by Judith A. Regner., Series 4; 19 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Caption title.; Cover title reads: Confidentiality of medical records.; Supported by a grant from the Health Care Financing Administration, DHEW, HCFA grant 18-P-27 321/3.
  - Medical malpractice pre-trial screening panels: a review of the evidence by Peter E. Carlin., 1980-10-01; Series 4; 53 pages: illustrations; 26 cm (Box 1, Folder 26)
    "October 30, 1980."; Includes bibliographical references.
  - The current status of state community mental health service legislation compiled by Gail E. Toff., 1984-08-01; Series 4; 105 pages; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 27)
    "August 1984."; "Compiled by the Intergovernmental Health Policy Project, George Washington University with the assistance of the National Association of State Mental Heath Program Directors."--Cover.
  - Mental health: patients' rights by Judith A. Regner., 1979; Series 4; 13 leaves; 28 cm. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Caption title.; Cover title: Mental health: voluntary and involuntary admissions/patient rights.; Supported by a grant from the Health Care Financing Administration, DHEW, HCFA Grant 18-P-27 321/3.
  - Mental Health: A Snapshot of 1980 Laws, Series 4 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - The regulation of free-standing psychiatric hospitals: results of a 1992 survey by Claire Helf., Series 4; 36 pages: illustrations; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Audiovisual materials in the Himmelfarb Library., 1974-09-01; Series 4; viii, 52 pages, 53-88 leaves; 28 cm (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Catalog prepared under the direction of Helene Zubkoff.; Cover title.; New format for printed catalog incorporating an information retrieval system.
  - The Social Security Administration: an inter-disciplinary study of disability evaluation by George J. Goldsborough, Jr., William G. Tinsley, and Arnold C. Sternberg., 1963; Series 4; 2 parts in 4 volumes; 29 cm (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Part 1. The administrative determination of permanent and total disability.--Part 2. The judicial concept of disability under the Social Security Act.